# **KYLE W. SINGLETON**

#### kwsingleton@ucla.edu

### **SUMMARY**

Biomedical Engineering PhD with focus in medical informatics and disease modeling. Experience leading a team in program design, implementation, and deployment and facilitating communication between engineering, medical, and clinical personnel. Proficient at data cleaning and model creation with SPSS, R, and MATLAB; moderate experience with additional programming languages.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of California, Los Angeles**

Los Angeles, CA

Doctor of Philosophy, Biomedical Engineering

June 2016 (Expected)

Dissertation: Establishing methods for prognostic graphical model adjustment across observational cohorts

Advisors: Alex A.T. Bui and William Hsu

**University of Virginia** 

Charlottesville, VA

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering

May 2006

Minor: Computer Science

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Graduate Student Researcher**

2012 - Present

UCLA Medical Imaging Informatics, Los Angeles, CA

- Supervised graduate student team, reviewing 500+ cancer cases for prognostic disease model evaluations.
- Implemented novel techniques for generalizing models between public and local data domains.

### **National Library of Medicine Fellow**

2008 - 2012

UCLA NLM Medical Imaging Informatics Training Program, Los Angeles, CA

- Programmed and supported a tablet based system used to survey 10,000+ patients in three Los Angeles clinics.
- Completed coursework in medical informatics, statistics, and machine learning.

Post-baccalaureate Fellow 2006 - 2008

National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD

Section on Stroke Diagnostics and Therapeutics, NINDS

- Designed new imaging workflow, accelerating availability for stroke research tasks.
- Developed a 100 patient case MRI stroke atlas.

## **Undergraduate Researcher**

2005 - 2006

Computational Systems Biology Lab, Charlottesville VA

Collaborated with two students to create metabolic network reconstruction of Leishmania major.

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: C++, Java, R, C#, ASP.NET, MATLAB, PHP, IDL

Informatics Tools: MATLAB, R, SPSS, RapidMiner, Weka, GENIE Medical Data Standards: DICOM, HL7, XML, OWL, UMLS, HIPAA

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Singleton KW, Speier W, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Motivating the additional use of external validity: examining transportability in a model of glioblastoma multiforme. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2014;2014:1930–9.

Singleton KW, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Transfer and transport: incorporating causal methods for improving predictive models. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2014;:amiajnl–2014–002968. doi:10.1136/amiajnl-2014-002968